MUHAMMAD QADIR

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

mahdimq@gmail.com 🚱 mahdimq.github.io/portfolio/ 📞 7039810226 in muhammad-qadir

PROFILE

Full stack software engineer experienced in Web Development, JavaScript, DOM Manipulation, Event-Driven Programming, Git/Terminal/Github, Modern JavaScript and Testing, AJAX, jQuery, ReactJS, Redux, SQL, PostgreSQL, Flask, Node, Express, Data Structures and Algorithms. With an obsession for writing clean code and innovative solutions. A formal Surgical Neurophysiologist for over 10 years, working against the clock and under stress is second nature. Excellent organizational skills with great attention to details, quickly become an asset to any growth minded firm.

SKILLS

JavaScript, Python, Node.js, Flask, HTML, CSS, ReactJS, Express.js, Jinja, Jasmine, Jest, PostgreSQL, MaterialUI, Styled Components, jQuery, Redux, Bootstrap

PROJECTS

The Watchlist Nov. 2020

Implemented a responsive single page app with React, Redux, Styled Components using Node/Express for backend and PostgreSQL as a database. Using bcrypt for authentication and multiple 3rd party APIs for data aggregation with PostgreSQL. Used throttling feature to slow down API calls as well as added a YouTube component to view movie trailers.

Foodie App July 2020

Built a dynamic webpage using Jinja template as a UI. Python and Flask as server side backend and PostgreSQL for a database. CSRF security with form validation as well as bcrypt authentication for user registration and login. Consumed 3rd party API to access over 380,000 recipes and cached the searched data with PostgreSQL to minimize API calls. Using Axios and jQuery libraries, implemented asynchronous search and cuisine selection.

EXPERIENCE

King Fahad Specialist Hospital, Surgical Neurophysiologist, Saudi Arabia

Mar. 2016 - Current

Over 10 years of Intraoperative Neuromonitoring and Clinical EEG experience with minimum supervision. Setting up various protocols for IOM devices catered towards specific surgical cases. Redesigned and improved the policies and procedures to achieve greater efficiency for the center and better outcomes for patients. Reduced setup times by over an hour, and implemented remote monitoring for 100% of the cases.

Springboard, Software Engineering Student/Fellow

May 2020 - Dec. 2020

Description: 800+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects. Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.

NuVasive Inc, Senior Intraoperative Neurophysiologist, San Diego, CA

July 2009 - Mar. 2016

Perform Intraoperative Neuromonitoring (IOM) during spine and cranial surgeries.

Participate in research aimed at improving the field of IOM and development of regional service volume.

Responsible for the preparation of the patient, conducting various electroneurodiagnostic studies, and the collection of information pertinent to the interpretation of tests.

EDUCATION

Springboard Software Engineering Certification

May 2020 - Dec. 2020

Certification Software Engineering

Virginia Commonwealth University Bachelor of Science Biomedical Engineering Jan. 2006 - May 2008